A Finding Aid to the Paul Vanderbilt Papers, 1854-1992, bulk 1945-1992, in the Archives of American Art AAA.vandpaul
Archives of American Art
- Professional Files, 1854-1991; Series 8; 11.7 Linear feet Boxes 13-24
  - Graphic History Society, 1945-1976; 8.2
    - Correspondence (Box 18)
      - I-K, 1952-1957 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - L, 1952-1957 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - M, 1952-1957 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - N, 1952-1955 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Never Mailed, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - O-P, 1953-1957 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Q-R, 1952-1955 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - S, 1952-1957 (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Special Libraries Association, 1952-1954 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence (Box 19)
      - T-V, 1952-1957 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - W, 1952-1955 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Y-Z, 1952-1954 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Davidson, Marshall B., Secretary-Treasurer, 1953-1957 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Directors, 1952-1953 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Directory Notes, 1950-1953 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Executive Committee, Pending, 1953-1957 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Executive Committee, Closed, 1953-1954 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Expenses, 1952-1956 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Eye to Eye (Box 19)
      - General Leads, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 10-11)
      - Bulletin, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Bulletin, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Bulletin, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Finished Copy, 1953-1954 (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Future Expansion, circa 1953 (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - No. 1 Used Copy, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - No. 2 Used Copy, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - No. 3 Used Copy, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - No. 4 Used Copy, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Operations for Current Issue, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Production and Budget, 1952-1955 (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Prospective Articles, 1945-1956 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Eye to Eye (Box 20)
      - Prospective Articles, 1945-1956 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - File Copies, 1952-1955 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Fundraising, 1953-1955 (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
    - Funds Forwarded to the Treasurer, 1953-1957 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Incorporation and Bylaws, 1952-1953 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Index, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - McClintock, Gilbert, 1953-1955 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Membership, circa 1953 (Box 20, Folder 10-15)
    - Membership Prospects, circa 1953 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Metal Stamp, circa 1953 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Notes, Errands for Next Trip to New York, 1950s (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Notes, "Look Into", 1952-1954 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Notes, News and Queries, 1950-1954 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Photographic Collections and Organizations, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Photography History and Photographers, 1939-1951 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Publicity, 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
    - Reports, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Special Collections, 1946-1954 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Special Projects, 1945-1955 (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
    - State Survey, 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - State Survey, Coordination with Other Projects, 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Subscription and Billing, 1953-1957 (Box 21, Folder 10-11)
    - Survey of Collections Related to States, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Television, 1939-1954 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Temporary Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Zig Zag Monthly Publication, 1953-1957 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1854-1989; 8.3
    - General, 1954-1989 (Box 21, Folder 16-17)
    - Activities, 1955-1966 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Administrative Documents, 1958-1960 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Art Programs, 1957-1967 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Annual Reports, 1958-1961 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Classification System for Pictorial Material, circa 1950 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Conference, "Photographs as Cultural Resources", 1982-1984 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1966 (Box 21, Folder 24-25)
    - Exhibitions of Photographs by Paul Vanderbilt, 1961-1966 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Exhibitions, 1956-1963 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Image Bank in Vancouver, Canada, circa 1971 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Indexing, Termatrex System, circa 1970 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Initial Contacts, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Johnstone, Robert, Naturescapes, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Memorandum on the Photography of America, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Milwaukee County Historical Society, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Motion Pictures, 1935-1963 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - National Portrait Gallery Fellowship, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - National Project in Agricultural Communications, 1958-1959 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1954-1960 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Our Own Time (1964) (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Photocopies of Images, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Photographic Field Trip Reports, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Planning and Administrative Memos, 1955-1960 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Proposal for Master of Arts in Popular Culture at Bowling Green State University, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Society for Photographic Education, Journal of Student Work, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Text Published by Society of Photographic Education, circa 1985 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Typography, 1854-1963 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Wisconsin Magazine of History, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Other Professional Activities, 1927-1991; 8.4
    - American Association for State and Local History, General, circa 1970s (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - American Association for State and Local History, Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - American Association for State and Local History, Evaluation, circa 1978 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - American Association for State and Local History, Evaluation Lecture, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - American Association for State and Local History, Film, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - American Association for State and Local History, Pensacola Historical Society, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - American Association for State and Local History, Seminar Questionnaires, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - American Association for State and Local History, Wisconsin, 1952-1954 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - American Iconographic Society, 1953-1957 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Apeiron, 1978-1988 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Apeiron, "Eye of the West: Camera Vision and Cultural Consensus" by Peter M. Schlessinger, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Apeiron, Letters, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Apeiron, Panels, circa 1981 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Apeiron, Panels Exhibition, 1982-1987 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Apeiron, Salford Electronics Photometer, 1971-1986 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Apeiron Workshops Discussion with Ralph Gibson, Mary Ellen Mark, and Students, 1978; Includes 1 sound cassette. (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Army Field Information Agency Microfilm Project, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Bibliotechnics, 1939-1950 (Box 22, Folder 39-41)
    - Bibliotechnics, Technical Matters, 1933-1954 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1973-1977 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Consultant, George Eastman House, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Consultant, Grand Rapids, Michigan Evaluation, 1972-1973 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Consultant, Hine Collection, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Consultant, Huntington Library and Art Gallery, 1931; 1950 (Box 23, Folder 5, Folder 6)
    - Consultant, Library of the Metropolitan Club, circa 1950s (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Consultant, Navy, 1941-1942 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Consultant, New Jersey Historical Society, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Consultant, Pensacola Historical Society, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - E. Weyhe Prints and Books, Plan for Library, circa 1940s (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Fairmount Park Institute Report, circa 1930s (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Farm Security Administration, General, 1940-1987 (Box 23, Folder 13-14)
    - Farm Security Administration, Charges of Fakes, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Farm Security Administration, Classification System, circa 1940s (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Farm Security Administration, Photographic File, 1942-1944 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Farm Security Administration, Procedures for Staff Under Roy Stryker, 1941-1943 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Farm Security Administration, Roy Stryker, 1939-1942 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Farm Security Administration, Writings, circa 1940s (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Farm Security Administration-Office of War Information, Content and Outlines, 1940s (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Farm Security Administration-Office of War Information, Descriptive Catalog Sheets, circa 1940s (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Farm Security Administration-Office of War Information, Outline by Edwin Kasskam, circa 1940s (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Office of War Information, 1940s (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Historical Society of Pennsylvania, Committee Objectives, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Jersey Shore "(Film?)", circa 1973 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Joint Committee on Materials for Research, 1934-1939 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Lecture Documents, Copy for Slides, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Lecture Documents, Miscellaneous, 1972-1981 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Lecture Documents, Rochester Institute of Technology, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Library Company of Pennsylvania, circa 1938 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Library of the Pennsylvania Museum of Art, 1933-1939 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1927-1941 (Box 23, Folder 33-34)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, Lantern Slide Project, 1936-1937 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, Union Catalog of Art Books, 1941 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Photography Projects, 1953-1989 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Professional Concerns, 1945-1991 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Restitution of Fine Arts and Archives in Germany, 1945-1946 (Box 23, Folder 39-40)
    - Society of Photographic Education Conference in Green Bay, Wisconsin, 1981-1982 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Travel to Canada, 1950-1974 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Travel to Europe with Chicago Council of Foreign Affairs, 1975-1981 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Visual Studies Workshop, 1973-1979 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Workshop Proposal on Juxtaposition, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Photographic Materials, 1912-1980s; Series 9; 0.5 Linear feet Box 24
  Photographs are by Vanderbilt, of Vanderbilt by Homer Page, of the Prints and Photographic Division Staff at the Library of Congress, and of George Talbot. Additionally, negatives of images for the Farm Security Administration, and microfilm with images of bibliography cards and photographs are also included.
  - Paul Vanderbilt, 1913-1980s (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Paul Vanderbilt with Others, 1912-1982 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Paul Vanderbilt Working at the Library of Congress by Homer Page, 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - By Paul Vanderbilt, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Prints and Photographic Division Staff at the Library of Congress by Paul Vanderbilt, circa 1950s (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - George Talbot, circa 1980s (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Microfilm, Bibliography Cards, circa 1950s (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Microfilm and Negatives of Photographs for the Library of Congress, circa 1950s (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Negatives, Farm Security Agency, circa 1950s (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Negatives, Various Subjects, circa 1950s (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Sound Recordings, circa 1980s; Series 10; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 24-25
  There are fourteen unlabeled and unidentified sound recordings.
  - Unidentified Sound Recordings, circa 1980s; 6 sound tape reels (Box 24, Folder 14-16)
  - Unidentified Sound Recordings, circa 1980s; 4 sound tape reels; 4 Sound cassettes (Box 25, Folder 1-3)